hi welcome to everyone's favorite
segment mailbag let's get straight into
it this one's from uh Rob Wheels good on
your Rob he's from Oakland in New
Zealand hi to all my New Zealand
viewers sorry had to make the joke but
yeah I know Australia has more sheep
than New Zealand but you know we can't
help but call them sheep shaggers so
thank you let's see what Rob has sent in
it was uh crushing everything on my
mailbag shelf over there oh more hang
on so we'll get this out of the road
jeez it's a bit Loosey Goosey in the
packaging but uh oh oh hello
hello Tada it's a projector with a
couple of other
miscellaneous what's a REV control Smart
Le program card I got no idea what that
is
what's for programming leads I don't
know and some sort of little um Power
speed control power brick or something
is there a
note
no
no there's no Noe by the way if you want
my handdrawn fluxgate condenser uh uh
fluxgate condenser t-shirt then I'll
provide a link down below to the
Teespring store where if I get 15 I
think they will print it Beauty so this
is an NEC
vt700 projector here um 2008 geez that's
pretty ancient uh yeah apparently it
doesn't work well this was all sent as
broken Electronics but uh basically it's
just a PC projector because um yeah it's
basically DVI and uh computer no uh uh
HDMI sort of like uh TV stuff there's
our lens and it's probably I don't know
was this a cheapy back in the day not
entirely sure
push what do i p oh look there we go
stand neat anyway 2 minute tear down
let's go and there's the lamp I believe
that thing is Cactus contains Mercury
oops interesting lens Arrangement that
the uh lamp goes through there H there
we have it that's inside it's quite uh
choc a block really main board on the
top it's got the uh tactile uh buttons
on the top that uh went directly to the
switches we got a fan over here what
brand is that it's just some made in
China thing I don't know whatever we got
a Dicky little speaker on the back
nothing fancy pancy is that a is that a
blower maybe that could be a
blower I don't know not quite sure I'm
going to have to take this thing apart a
lot more it's actually going to
require uh quite a bit of effort to take
this apart so I think it's more than a
2minute uh tear down so I might have to
leave this if I've got enough time at
the end of shooting the rest of uh these
mailbag stuff then I'll do it otherwise
it'll have to be a separate video sorry
Reventon smartled program card I've got
no idea what this is at all but yeah
okay um interesting uh enclosure for it
you can see the uh dip standoff
4digit lead display in there and uh then
they' just got some buttons looks like
are they is that molded into the top
case just going down to the tactile
domes there with some switches that
that's just a rather unusual enclosure
so all it is some buttons some headers a
four-digit display and an atml 0 Mega
here and and a side laabs cp2102 USB
youart Chipen well that's all she wrote
and well okay there's nothing wrong with
that if you find a niche application
that does some smart thing you can sell
a million of your widgets that you know
real simple to design and do it's all a
matter about Market requirements so
there is I don't know what does this do
it programs some leads or something item
value reset okay speed passion I don't
know
interesting could have sold a million of
them who knows and it comes with this
companion thing the uh Speed Passions
probably their car thing sort of looks
and feels Automotive took the screws off
that and uh not much uh doing inside
there are they reasonably uh compact
though that's a yeah that's a that's a
uh secondary board so that's the that's
probably the controller board excuse
being completely rough here but some
mosfets driving some Motors or leads or
whatever actually it makes sense that
they're on the bottom side cuz that's
the heat sink so you want those mosfets
attached down to the heat sink so that's
all it is tiny little uh controller and
oh okay so you program do you use that
to program this that other thing to
program this perhaps maybe that's how it
works and oops I could smell this before
I could see it um yeah we're blowing the
ass out of a few mosfets there Magic
Smoke has escaped active ingredient in
every component is that part of the dye
still stuck to the case inside there oh
wow wow extreme overload next up one
from Keith Williams thank you very much
Keith he's from Kansas City uh in the
United States of America never been to
Kansas we're not in Kansas anymore
Toto it's all I know of Kansas
sorry I know that's pretty bad but uh
you know
anyway ah all right let's see what Keith
sent got padding we got a note and
and padding that's it let's have a
look come on get out of here get out of
here we got another little brick looks
like um some sort of regulator brick I'm
not sure if we can yeah we can do a
two-minute tear down on that because
it's looks like it's not potted it's
just a clip it's just a clip I can like
jeez I could yeah I could almost get
that off with my fingernail I think
almost two minute tear down and Keith is
only 15 good on you Keith he's sent in
this little puppy and uh it's a DC todc
regulator for model airplanes and
helicopters to regulate the main battery
voltage up to 50 volts wow really okay
didn't think they were that high jeez
that's a lot of like multiple batteries
in series or is there one big like 48
volt battery or something crazy anyway
to around 6 to8 power the receiver and
the servos attached to the chart from
the manufacturer showing it's currently
set to 6.5 Vols me and a few friends uh
we're hoping I could tear it down and
tell us what I think maybe put it
through a load test to see if it lives
outo ratings he wants to know if it's
any good or not well let's have a squiz
first thing I'm going to look at is the
wires and they look pretty beefy is that
16 gauge there that looks you know that
looks good enough to carry the current
so no worries there but here's your
problem maximum continuous current and
Keith's giving us a chart here and I've
calculated the output Powers multiply
the voltage times the current up to
anywhere from 240 wats at uh lower input
voltages up to 384 watts output power
capability at uh 48 volts input with
this little Dicky heat sink are you
kidding me um because basically even if
you're 90% efficient okay you you might
be able to get higher than that if you
optimized it for one particular output
voltage but this is a fairly wide range
right so this is you know so this thing
is not going to if they get 90%
efficiency in this thing they're doing
really well 90% efficiency you've got to
means that you're going to be dropping
38 watts in this anywhere from 24 watts
to 38 watts in this pissant little heat
SN here I call right away and I
had a double check this uh size heat
sink here it's about 28x 28x 12 or
something like that we're talking about
6° C per watt at a couple of hundred uh
cubic feet per minute air flow okay
granted because this is on like a model
plane okay it could be you know they
could be getting air flow you know a ton
of air flow over the thing that's fine
but even that like you know six degrees
C per whatt are you kidding me and this
has to dissipate anywhere from 24 to 38
wat so maximum power you'd be talking
well over 150° C temperature rise on
this thing at you know under best case
conditions could be higher it's it it's
ridiculous there's the underside of it
at least it's got a conformal coating
you should be able to see the shine on
that so they've at least gone the extra
mile to keep the moisture out of this
thing but come on this is not going to
do a
384 wat continuous output power me
kidding me at least they got 105°
c-rated cap on
there anyway like totally inadequate you
know output capacitance but yeah I don't
know what it's you know it's driving so
riple like you know n whatever um but
jeez no come on come on anyone want to
have a guess as to what the maximum real
maximum output power this thing is I
don't know probably getting towards an
order of magnitude less than what
they're claiming so Keith wants to know
if I give it a thumbs up nope thumbs
down um especially for the rated power
otherwise you know you know it's okay if
they raided this thing uh properly you
know it' be fine but hey you know
they've done some fairly beefy Parts on
there and it it's probably going to work
reasonably up to a certain point but
apart from that but no hasn't got a
snowballs chance in hella meeting its
rating another one from the United
States of America H Andrew T rich thank
you very much he's from Boston
Massachusetts haven't been to Boston
either jeez I haven't been anywhere I
need to get out more it's bit hard when
you got a wife and two kids though let
me tell you anyway let's have a look oh
calculator Panasonic Panasonic 840 check
it out wow wonder how old that is hang
on
mid 70s what else we
got whoa oh
palmy Palm Pilot I've done uh Palm Pilot
tear Downs before I don't know if it was
the Palm 3 might have been anyway um I
did I I thought it was a rather good
video where I did like a timeline
compared the timeline of Palms these
were the duck guts before we had these
new fangled smartphones so anyway um 2
minute T on the Panasonic awesome oh
look at this baby the Panasonic 840 uh
1974 apparently I wonder how long a
lifespan it actually had oh oh oh oh
light comes on but it's the J 840 a u
for those playing long at home 6 volts
at half a watt wow oh I got sucking in
there that's not a l it looked like it
cuz I'm looking through the um the
camcorder screen here there that is
not that is not an indicator it's just
like a a mechanical like a little bit of
copper or something showing through
there oh my
goodness look at the
styling Andrew says that uh this puppy
does not work so I'll take his word for
it
a is that a
header yeah you bet you that's a header
oh wow look at that there we go oh look
oh look at that vacuum fluorescent
display oh thing of beauty look at those
white are they they jumpers they white
jumper links through hole jumper links
anyway it's a mat aidu there you go MN
5530 what's the calculator forensics on
this puppy can't do it because it
doesn't have any trig functions it's
just as they called in the trade a fall
banger and it's not a real display
unless it's got a nipple look at that I
love the nipple next up we have a
commercial one you can tell because it's
FedEx uh Joe average usually doesn't do
FedEx unless you're in one of those
countries that can get a really good
deal on FedEx certainly not Australia
[Music]
anyway jez this thing's a bit
unwieldy anyway struggle through with it
because it looks good it's all bit
something's come out got something
long light interesting
oh oh I think I might like this do it
turns out I actually ordered um this um
I completely forgot I order stuff and
just completely forget about it but
apparently um they knew who I was hi
Dave we really like the eev blog uh we
included some extra sample goodies opv
tape solar cell scky tape enjoy Infinity
PV there you go that's the logo in
Infinity yes Infinity PV there you go
thank you very
much doesn't say anyway they enjoy my
blog thank you very much these are
organic solar cells wow I'm going to
have to do a separate video on these I
can't do these Justice in the mail bag I
don't think but uh yeah these are
flexible organic solar cells a
excited what some whizbang new
technology and uh now I can't remember
why I order I ordered them cuz they're
cool but I wanted to I can't remember if
I had a specific idea for it either
video idea or project idea or both uh at
at the time and yeah these are um
flexible uh 3M backing tape on them
anyway let's take a look awesome
flexible organic solar CS Beauty hang
on oh I just love the genuine 3M
Adhesive
smell oh yeah oh I'm quite excited about
these I'll show you in better uh detail
in a minute but I've got a couple of
these Infinity uh PV uh test samples
what they are and uh strips as well but
these ones are kind of like more useful
they're designed for like classroom uh
demonstrators and things like that and
yes they are completely flexible solar
cells like this no worries these have
adhesive strips on the back you can
stick them in uh various places you can
cut them to length and what they are is
they're organic solar cells most
important thing about these is that
they're actually printed uh they're
printed photovoltaic technology so they
print them on these uh large format roll
printers so they print them on like
rolls that are you know like hundreds of
meters long or something like that so
can print them as long as you like and
you just cut them uh you just cut them
to size to length uh to the ones that
you you require so the manufacturing
cost of these things is incredibly low
or I should correct that and say has the
potential to be incredibly low I'm not
sure what the uh cost is at the moment
probably high because there're still not
you know not real mainstream technology
but the fact that you can um print these
on really cheap uh printers instead of
you know solar cell Manufacturing quite
the regular ones that you're used to on
your rooftops and things like that
they're you know quite an evolved uh
process and these are not terribly
efficient by the way we're only talk of
1.5 to 7% uh efficiency as opposed to
you know like maybe 20% efficiency for
like a rooftop uh solar panel but the
fact that you can actually print these
on Roll printers uh and they're uh thin
completely like less than5 mm flexible
Bend bendable semi-transparent can get
different funky colors excellent um and
you can get uh any length limit as I
said and even the production of them is
energy efficient uh you don't need any
High uh Power High uh temperature uh
processors uh no vacuums no uh
evaporation uh type you know processes
no clean rooms nothing like that it uses
an additive manufacturing uh technology
fast energy payback time I you'd
probably I'll link in the website down
below they've probably got more detail
and low environmental impact non-toxic
or no scarce elements or anything like
that well they claim to be uh recyclable
um probably not 100% but you know you
can probably do it and here's the uh
solar foil which I don't have uh these
ones are efficiency only 2 to 4% not
great but hey they could offer more uh
bang per buck so you wouldn't use these
in you know massive solar farm projects
or something like that but uh Hey for
you know if really low cost and flexible
and you can use them in all sorts of
different uh scenarios you can't use
traditional solar cells in then they
could be a winner uh typically 1 to four
watts per meter that'll depend on the
width I guess they send sell different
width uh types um you can cut connect
and integrate them yourself and uh they
can have the adhesive on the back just
like this and oh I love the smell of the
3M
adhesives oh it's just wonderful and we
don't have these here but uh Infinity uh
PV looks like they do uh some like test
systems and things like this uh laser
beam induced current mapping so they
actually use here's a little block
diagram they use a PC based uh test
system hook it up and then they got a
scanny laser here can scan over the
solar cell and um you can induce a
current in there so to map it out and to
100% characterize the surf these surface
of these things that's pretty neat and
they've even got a solar simulator as
well hey that's pretty it generates
homogeneous light simulation over a
large area with various filters and all
sorts of stuff to uh test your solar
panels fantastic so here's the classroom
demonstrator they got these uh studs
here fantastic positive and negative
terminals uh AG no recycling so there's
uh of course they got silver in these
things silver is a big uh usage High
usage component in regular solar panels
i' be using those for the the contacts
and things like that but yeah this is
going to I presume it's only like a two-
layer process I can't like tear it down
or anything like that presumably you
have to shine them on the uh top surface
like that or do you also get I maybe you
wouldn't get the same efficiency but
maybe you can shine it from the other
side anyway these are really Jazzy you
can fold them like this
fantastic all right let's measure the
short circuit current sh this is an easy
uh test for solar uh panels you can't
damage them by doing this not just these
ones other ones as well measure the
short circuit Uh current and we're
looking with the lab lights here I've
got about a th000 lux on the uh bench
here and we're getting about 500
microamps there you go and can we yeah
we can just Shield out one of them and
it will
slowly decrease yep there you go linear
decrease pretty much yep yep happy with
that nice and unfortunately I can't take
it outside and test it because well it's
uh yep 600 p.m. so what happens if I
flip that
over there we go you still get something
out of it but yeah as I suspected uh not
as good as efficiency basically drops in
half when
you uh get light from the other side but
they're semi-transparent that's why it
works and if I shine a torch onto this
thing Wham we're overloaded I have to go
to milliamps oh 5 seven milliamps look
at
that what a Bobby desler oh jeez you
might be able to get 10 milliamps out of
that by shining a torch on it so anyway
I think these are really Jazzy I'm going
to experiment with these probably
mightbe a actually uh have a around have
a play around and fully characterize
this in a separate video but I'll link
them in down below hello there Infinity
pv.com very Jazzy and very promising
technology too this um you know like
basically additive printing technology
to print solar cells fantastic not
hugely efficient yet but hey they'll
probably get better I think it's
probably unlikely that they're ever
going to match uh proper in quote marks
you the real high efficiency uh solar
technology that we used to these days
and that's just growing and growing and
growing and I think these ones are
always going to be less efficient by the
nature of the printing processes and you
know things like that they're not as
optimized but they're designed for low
cost and you know easy manufacturing and
also it's the as they talked about the
um ecological footprint of actually
manufacturing these things is going to
be a hell of a lot lower so you'd have
to go through the whole life cycle
analysis of how much energy is required
overall energy required to produce a reg
rooftop panel uh for example you know a
poly poly crystalline panel or whatever
compared to an equivalent output of a
printed one like this and you know look
at do the whole life cycle which is a
complex thing that's you know
manufacturing the raw materials mining
them and transporting them and
processing them and then transporting
them again and then the manufacturing
process of the panel itself and then Shi
you know testing and shipping everything
else so life cycle analysis was quite
complex so it' be interesting if anyone
actually has any data on that of these
compared to regular photo voltaics then
please let us know anyway these are fun
I have to do another video on these
great
[Music]
we got ourselves another FedEx jobby
extremely urgent um FedEx Express sorry
it's been sitting here forever um this
is from uh siligo um silly go as I like
to call them um I think they're having a
second or third suck of the sav they've
been on here before so let's test this
uh worked look at that marvelous modern
technology and we've got yep a couple of
little chippies and Boards let's take a
look and I'm sure we've seen the on the
blog before they're having a second suck
of the sav these are I'll show you the
data sheet here these are a mixed signal
for want of a better word a mixed signal
plld uh really like uh they've got like
macro cells like uh plds and but or you
know SL fpgas you know they've got some
serial coms in there they've got analog
comparators they've got filters and
things like that and you can switch them
all in neat little niche use uh
components and check out what theyve
sent me here because these are such
little bastard packages you can't
possibly use them this is a zero
insertion Force socket uh converts the
chips into a little uh Jewel in line .1
in header very nice but look at how
small this
is yeah that's can you see the pins in
there can you see them can you see them
you might have to watch this in like
full HD to be able to to see the pins in
that what a bastard package but hey
obviously their target market is you
know real dense uh stuff so the packages
are what they are so this is a really
nice to get the adapter like this to be
able to uh you know breadboard play
around with these things um at the
Prototype level awesome so oh if you
want to take a look at them I'll link
them in down below we got one from
Germany hi to all my German viewers uh
from an yeah an weasel wisel
wesle I'm not sure anyway from hburg in
Germany I don't know where hburg is got
some nice flower stamps on here Beauty
um it says Electronic Component yeah
that narrows it down I think I can just
uh slice and dice
that let's have a look what art oh that
looks like a dongle that looks like a
dongle old school you remember those you
plug them onto your uh parallel or
serial port and you would enable
uh software and uh stuff like that geez
I designed one back in the day for
somebody oh wow anyway let's have a look
at the note greetings from the hars in
Germany um as announced by oh yes email
yes I think he uh said he was going to
um send this dongle maybe a two-minute
tear down if it's not potted so Arie has
sent through this Sentinel super pro
dongle let's see if we can take it apart
anyone remember these what's it for it's
was software licensing at his father's
company doesn't say assume that software
yeah it does it basically looks for the
presence of the dongle This Is How They
copy protected software back in the day
they used uh what was that is that
rainbow something or other so that's the
company and Sentinel super pro would be
the dongle and there were dongle
companies back in the day I'm sure
there's uh none of them still around
made in the Philippines I my viewers in
the Philippines well there's an Annie
climax we just got a chip on board blob
and that's basically it some of the
lines are straight through um this is
designed to plug into the parallel port
of course and uh they were all the rage
back in the80s parallel PP dongles I can
remember um Altium which was uh called
protel at the time that was their
official name they used to have a dongle
for their auto tracks uh software
version
1.61 and then which was Auto TRS for
Doss yes Doss Microsoft MS DOS thank you
very much real operating system um and
they had a version 1.61 I can remember
when 1.61 ND came out and ND stood for
no dongle so it no longer required the
dongle you could just copy the software
and Bob's your uncle you've got it so I
don't know maybe someone out there has
details on this particular one whether
or not it was encrypted or did anything
fancy like that it was probably just
simple and I designed one of these uh
back in the day and no it was didn't use
encryption or anything like that a
common technique was just to use you
know basically Jelly Bean uh logic shift
registers and stuff like that and you
can just uh encode the data and then you
potted the thing and yeah you could
reverse engineer it but most people
didn't bother there was no internet back
then you know so it was like you know
people couldn't you just commonly share
the knowledge or whatever if you did uh
reverse engineer it so you know just a
simple uh you know Jelly Bean logic way
of uh doing it just shifting out some
hidden bits or something if it didn't if
the correct bits didn't come out then
you know boom that was it it the
software just wouldn't work and from
memory it was actually difficult to uh
circumvent these in software cuz uh most
of the software back in the day would
talk to the serial Port Hardware
directly so intercepting that and just
you know feeding in the correct data or
doing whatever if you you know you could
sniff it uh to see you sniff the pins
get a logic analyzer in there see what
it's doing um but to actually you know
duplicate that um I think most people
probably duplicate in Hardware back in
the day jeez that's really stretching my
memory now bloody dongles I've got a
letter old school letter from MB it's
even typed it's from a typewriter
brilliant um a stamp from the cesa
republ is that like the Czech Republic
or something
cesa there you go can you see
that anyway let's open it old school
letter typed doesn't get any better geez
those were the days I can remember when
I was selling kits and and software back
in the day when I was a we youngster and
um yeah people had send me letter or I
got my articles published people and
send me letters probably still have a
lot of them lying around and so I got a
oh a postcard oh oh no they're photos
they're photos excellent from oh love
the clock oh big fan of clock
towers it's not just because Back to the
Future oh I really like
a loves when I debunk stuff like the
batter rizer yep brilliant um you really
disappointed me on the 833 video when
you talked about
faith what oh God why Jesus why not
Allah why not
anyway it was the Czech Republic and oh
that's a gorgeous Clock Tower where is
that oh wow I love that
beautiful I don't make them like that
anymore now I know some people think
this is off topic and I shouldn't even
bother with this but hey this is the
mail bag segment I open the mail and I
talk about what's in it somebody has
sent me a letter about religion and in
fact my previous uh comment on it which
they're uh taking uh exception to um
he's disappointed um male bag 883 I
presume it is or whatever 883 was I'm
talking about legitimate concern opinion
I am disappointed because you're totally
screwed up with logic okay let's see
where I was wrong I was not expecting
something like this from you do you want
to base your life on science yes of
course I do well then start with logic
first okay I am referring to these exact
words you said why Jesus why not Allah
why not Buddha why not anyone of the you
know hundreds or even thousands of gods
that have been worshiped over the years
by people who believe just as much as
you do and they can't all be right so it
is almost certain that well none of them
are right and that's exactly I'm pretty
sure that's exactly what I uh said in a
video a while back if there was a
meter you would blow up the
protection fuse with this sentence here
we go here's his logic let's go through
it okay I'll give it a fair sucker the
have let's assume you have 2,000 kids in
a school and you ask them how much is 6
+ 9 all 2,000 kids will give you a
different answer okay well if they don't
know what that is okay fair enough there
are hundreds thousands of kids saying
something different and they can't all
be right so it is almost certain that
none of them are right correct well that
is exactly what you said no it's not
this is the most piss poor analogy I've
ever heard in my life because
this is a question about mathematics it
has a 100% certifi certifiably
demonstrably true answer so you
can of course I would not say none of
them are right I would in this instance
of course I would not say none of them
right so right there the analogy is
completely and utterly busted it's it's
the worst analogy I've ever heard of
course there is a kid who is Right among
the 2,000 kids surprisingly the only kid
who says the fact that uh 1,999 kids
gave the wrong answer does not imply
that the only kid answering is also
wrong of course I never said I was not
implying that
unbelievable nor does it reduce the
probability that there is actually
somebody who is right how he's right who
is right of course because these are
this is apples and oranges you cannot
compare these two it is a fundamentally
demonstrably bad analogy kid 15 is it I5
is not less or more probable to be right
because uh because around him there are
more or less kids agreeing or
disagreeing with him the same applies
when you're talking about Gods I'm glad
you bought that up I completely agree
and I I've probably said that many times
before uh the fact that there might be a
billion other people who believe the
same thing you do does not make it true
it's only evidence that makes something
true the same applies when you talk
about Gods yes there are thousands of
gods worshiped around the world that
does not imply almost none of them is
right uh they could all be wrong but
there could be one who is Right both
options are logically valid you cannot
logically say that disagreement implies
nobody's right you do not have any
freaking logic base to state so I'm
sorry to tell you this Madia but that is
not how it works let's assume that there
are nine Gods okay that people believe
in nine different gods and then the 10th
option is there is no God they are not
all equally valid because the nine Gods
Not only have absolutely no evidence for
going for them but they're all
contradictory okay they they all hold
contradictory State contradictory
statements which means that they can't
you know like two of them can't be true
right so at best only one of them is
true but because they contradict each
other and that alone is in effect
evidence that they're actually all made
up they it's actually evidence so the
option the tenth option that there is no
God actually has some evidence behind it
as opposed to the other nine who are all
contradicting each other and have no
real verifiable evidence whatsoever so
the ninth option that there the 10th
option that there is no God is does not
have the same probability as one of the
other nine being true there's not one
chance in 10 of there being no God or
there's not one chance in 10 of the
Christian God being true uh for example
whatever flavor of the hundreds of
different flavors of Christianity you
want to pick that's not how it works the
lack of evidence does not sit on the
same level of probability as evidence
it's just not how it works sorry Mia
that is one of the worst analogies I've
ever heard but hey it's a common one
from religious people eh go figure so
what is more probable that the religion
that you believe in that you were just
by accident happened to have been Bor
into in a particular country and raised
up in a particular faith that that one
happens to be actually true when there's
absolutely no evidence for it when
there's hundreds or even thousands of
other religions or variations of
religions that all have different
viewpoints and contradictory viewpoints
with absolutely no evidence for any of
them and you're trying to assert that
they're all you know logically the same
probability no it's absurd and this one
I already opened cuz I thought it was a
letter uh sometime back actually I think
I might have uh tweeted it actually um
it's a letter from a lawyer um some
legal firm here in Australia and you
know when you first see it like you open
a letter from a lawyer god what have I
said now that's got me in trouble who's
suing me um no they want me to be an
expert uh witness on a case and no
thanks no way Jose and I get these
things at least a couple of times a year
um they sent me an email as well I've
already uh reply to them but they sent
me a formal letter as well and no I
turned down all these expert witness
cases it's just not worth the trouble
it's you know unless you're really
unless it was something massively high
high profile like it was you know the
Toyota uh case with you know the
accelerator pedal thing or something you
know something really important but this
is just some tinpot company here about
their soldering alleged defects I'll
show you it alleged defects in soldering
light assemblies the misters like I
don't want to get bogged down in that
yeah and they often say oh we'll give
you a handsome retainer for your time
and effort no it's not worth your time
and effort so here's one of these
typical letters that I get quite a few
of some of the key issues essential to
the dispute relate to aspects of alleged
defects of control boards soldering
light assemblies the MERS and Driver
boards our client has become aware of
your expertise yeah they've just Googled
you know PCB or circuit expert or
something I don't know my maybe my name
came came up in the list geez or the
timeline litigation requires that a
draft report be completed by the end of
March where this is an old letter and
therefore uh seeking to brief you in the
matter blah blah blah blah blah end of
February blah blah blah blah blah my CV
blah blah blah blah blah no thanks my
advice don't get involved in these
things they're just not worth your time
and effort getting through some older
ones just stuck at the back at the
bottom there sorry if you've been
sitting some of them are like many many
months they've been sitting here anyway
it doesn't say who it's from so uh
person unknown I think it's
Norway so hi to all my Norwegian viewers
assuming that's
correct
wa I have a couple of Parts greeting uh
just a greeting from Norway got it right
uh very much appreciate your work thank
you very much you managed to inspire
even a biologist to familiarize himself
with electronics which is impressive
thank you very much awesome love hearing
that sort of stuff included a three
pairs of formula banana plag adapters
that I find very practical oh that's
handy that's handy okay they um their uh
pins to go stick them in your breadboard
to Banana Jacks I don't actually have
any of those they're damn handy you know
I normally do it in a in a um madeen
himself obviously still don't say who
you are but thank you very much um very
handy I normally you know just have a
bit of wire sticking up and then I might
have a uh alligator clip lead to
something else you know that I just clip
on and it's daggy but that's nice to
connect up to probes or power or
anything like that that's really handy
and we've got an old
Altera PL wow that's old school and LH
o33 what's that LH o33 is that a
highspeed um like a real highspeed amp I
can't remember damn memory getting too
old there you have it these things are
com in real Handy make your own Easy
Peasy highly recommended wow an early
ala EP 910 epld raisable programmable uh
logic device basically 24 macro cells
inside this thing and here's a shot of
uh the macro cells and what they
actually contain and typical uh early
reconfigurable uh PL logic electrically
erasable um in this case which was a
fantastic Boon at the time you didn't
have to worry about any of that UV a
raising rubbish fantastic and the LH 33
wow can you still buy it um but yeah
this thing was the Ducks guts for a long
time if it isn't still the duck guts
anyway um High current uh wide bandwidth
high voltage amplifier very handy very
widely used in all sorts of you know
more high power applications basically
just a real high power voltage buffer
that's it it's not an amplifier just
just a buffer hi to all my Canadian
viewers this one's from Nicholas Gia
thank you very much Nicholas he's from
uh
Drummondville QC where's QC in Canada
not
sure it's not
Quebec is it no anyway let's see what
Nicholas has sent some postcards that'll
be nice because
it's it is the snow all that funny white
stuff which we don't get here yes we do
uh up in the snowy mountains there's
like a couple of places in Australia
where it snows regularly and uh yes
Quebec there you go
beautiful anyway what's in here
something tiny take a look and Nicholas
has sent in a classic here I don't have
one of these it's a n well originally
introduced in
1961 let's take it out here to protect
the pins tada one of the first
commercially available ic's look at that
oh looks like a Luna Lander it's got too
many legs but you know spidery craft
coming down land on the moon oh we're
almost out of
gas anyway got these from a science
teacher while he's in high school and
his dad owned the local TV repair shop
got a bunch of surplus uh parts and yeah
1961 V vintage RTL resistor transistor
logic not this TTL rubbish or Doo
transistor logic just transistors and
resistors and uh apparently these were
used in the um Apollo guidance computer
oh luckily I did the I look like a limb
there you go the Apollo guidance
computer um they used uh some of these
uh Fairchild stuff the um use
2800 uh micr logic there you go juel
Norgate IC to create the first computer
computer was running at 2 MHz 16bit
consumed 55 and weighed only 32 kg that
was like stunning for the day and
allowed us to land on the moon fantastic
anyway fantastic here's the original
data sheet for this thing and you can
see the uh it's got resistors and
transistors in it that's it uh this is
the Dual input um uh two input Norgate
there we go typical resistor values uh
450 and 640 ohms there you go wow
terrific but these things were you know
state-ofthe-art back in the day cuz you
would have had to have your four
transistors and or your resistors so
this saved a lot of space this was you
know state-of-the-art integration at the
time oh sorry this one actually
contained a duel two input uh Norgate so
we had two nor Gates inside the one
package there it is um it could fan out
uh to 16 other uh it could drive 16
other devices that wasn't too shabby
even today jeez 16 devices pretty good
and you can wire them as RS fli flop and
I'd love to power this puppy up and give
it a bell but unfortunately I don't have
time I got to race through the rest of
this mile bag we're back to Germany
again thank you very much Alexander
nasan um from Los
such in Germany don't know where it is
sorry let's have a
look no one these stupid tricky thing oh
goodness
fail fail file file file file file file
file it's got
wire wrapped
around s soldering
iron oh
my I feel dirty oh no and why do we have
why wrapped in here I've got to undo
that's not wire I think that's
solder probably the good lead stuff and
Alexander is sent in the soldering iron
of death I'm pretty sure we've seen one
of these before haven't we shocking uh
this is a two
22240 uh volt 60 wat unit and wow I mean
it cost
$2 40 including shipping from Hong Kong
I mean um unbelievable look at that
there's no strain relief at all that is
the worst quality feeling cable I've
ever felt in my entire life it is truly
horrendous and we like and it's just ah
it's Dicky ass
unbelievable if we open it
up and there yep there we go oh main
straight into the element no Earth in on
you
metal unbelievable do not use these
things these are just they literally are
a death trap I think hi welcome to
everyone's favorite segment mailbag and
once again there are some people
watching me live on this one there's my
little uh LogiTech C920 webcam and I'm
using uh I'm broadcasting to my second
Channel eev blog uh 2 Link is down below
at all there's not nothing else there's
just the single custom Asic chip which
say turnout for peanuts once they've got
their um once they've paid for the um
engineering on that